Priscilla Hamiter

253.324.4560 ● San Francisco, CA 94109 ● priscillahamiter.com phamiter253@gmail.com ● github.com/phamiter253

Committed, innovative Senior Engineering Manager with over 5 years of professional experience in web applications design, creative design, and leadership through excellent communication. Familiar with agile development of web apps and fast-paced, collaborative workflows. Comfortable debugging or troubleshooting front-end and back end development environments with computer programming and problem-solving skills. Can diagnose, develop, or manage a web applications ecosystem, including use cases with APIs. Known for reliability, influencing team culture, and programming prowess.

CORE SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Industry skills: Programming / Coding (Git / Github, see proficiencies below), Cloud Computing Platforms (AWS S3, EC2, Lambda, ACM, Route53, CloudFront, Lightsail, CodePipeline), DNS Management (GoDaddy, MediaTemple, Cloudflare, Google Domains), UI & web design; 3D Modeling (AutoCAD), graphic and photo editing, Image Authoring Tools (Adobe Animate, Photoshop, Illustrator); Content Management System (WordPress), Agile Software Development (Asana); troubleshooting & debugging.

Programming proficiencies: Python (Flask, Pandas, NumPy), Java, C, C#, JavaScript (Node, NPM, NVM, React, Redux, jQuery, Next, GraphQL, Gatsby, Next, D3, Chart, Axios, Ajax, Nuxt, Vue, Pug), HTML, CSS(Bootstrap, Bulma), SCSS, Sass, TypeScript, PHP, SQL.

Other skills: Mentorship, management, leadership; instructional design; Adobe Creative Cloud (Adobe Animate, Photoshop), Google Workspace, Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Outlook, OneDrive).

Customer Service Software (Zendesk).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rooster Grin Media | San Francisco, CA

Nov 2023 – Present Frontend Developer

Working with Frontend team to improve our Template websites implementation. Designing and building ADA complaint and custom websites for clients.

- Builds next-generation, ADA-compliant websites using Nuxt.js and AWS, ensuring optimized performance, scalability, and accessibility for all users.
- Develops customized websites by designing and implementing features aligned with business' branding.
- Presents websites to clients, conducting detailed walkthroughs and demonstrating all site components' functionality and design.

June 2022 – Nov 2023 Lead Web Developer Support

Problem-solved with clients, ensuring problems that arise are resolved in a timely & friendly manner. Managed and maintained over 900 websites.

- Set processes & guidelines for site templates, worked with Web Development Team for build and launch.
- Employed familiarity with WordPress APIs, open-source deployments, and creative tools in troubleshooting.
- Assisted clients requiring support, using superior technical skills to provide resolutions and improve client relationships.

Reactful Sep 2020 – Dec 2020 Software Engineer Intern | San Francisco, CA

Handled hands-on technical projects with responsive design requirements and highly scalable scrum-based development. Used provided roadmap for collaboration on engineering deliverables for frontend & backend development alike.

- Redesigned and implemented front end with React, Bootstrap, and custom CSS frameworks.
- Expanded backend functionality of Neon Juice API and implemented frontend connections.
- Brainstormed and created multiple wireframes and types of workflow for website builder/generator web application.

Girl Tech Power July 2019 - Aug 2019 Coding Workshop Instructor | San Francisco, CA

Utilized instructional design skills to communicate web standards, engineering best practices, and product development acumen. Aided in professional development of students learning backend architecture with mobile app and web technology.

- Created modern, original lesson plan on web-based Thunkable platform for building Android and iOS apps.
- Advised other instructors and students engaging with projects related to HTML, Python, and Alice.
- Mentored and facilitated multiple two-week workshop sessions on web technologies with 30+ middle school students.

University of San Francisco May 2019 – Dec 2019 Teacher Assistant | San Francisco, CA

Organized activities, quizzes, and classwork for new curriculum. Tutored students in class and during dedicated hours, helping students with missing work. Offered mentorship and constructive criticism or corrections on assignments and projects.

KÜDZOO Jun 2018 – Aug 2018 Remote Associate Product Management Intern | Manhattan, NY

Led project scope for new version of mobile application, creating wireframes for website based on user research and activity. Beta-tested new functionality ideas for the application that encourage user engagement with the intern team.

EDUCATION

University of San Francisco, CA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science